Run the Pinback guy will see this term called business documents that will be an input to some of our
processes and sometimes we'll have to update business documents.
What are business documents and why do I need them.
Business documents we're talking about things like the project business case the project charter the
project management plan and the benefits management plan.
That business documents are attached to these or affect these and they are used throughout the project.
Let's look at some opportunities here where we have some business documents.
So first of all we have business documents for Project performance and we're talking about here are
phase gates within the project.
So a new term at the end of a phase before I can move into the next phase there's a review of what I've
done so far that review is called a phase gate that I can't go to the next phase until the prior phase
is 100 percent done accounted for financially and signed off on.
So that review is called a phase gate will a business document that would be attached to this would
be a review of what was I supposed to spend when was I supposed to be done with that phase.
What were the deliverables.
So the business documents are tied to the phase gates of that project.
Then we have actual performance compared against what we predicted in our business document.
So estimates.
So I have cost estimates and schedule estimates.
Well did I actually deliver what was promised if I did great if I did not.
There needs to be what's called an exceptions report or a variance report a way to communicate why I
did not hit my target.
Why did not hit my key performance indicators my K.P. eyes.
So why was I late or over budget or both or whatever the case may be.
I also have to make some decisions at phase gate at the end of phases number of phase gate.
Is also known as a Kill Point because it's an opportunity to kill the project based on performance.
So if we could have rules set up prior to the project going that if you are more than 30 percent over
budget at the end of a phase then we're going to scrap the project.
We're not going to move forward.
Or if you're more than X-amount days late and you're likely to not hit the deadline for the whole project
so we're going to scrap it.
So it's a killer point.
So continue to the next phase that can be a decision at a phase gate.
So you can't move on to the next gate or to the next phase because performance is bad and so we cancel
the project or you can go on to the next phase.
But we're going to do a modification.
So based on how much you've spent or the lateness we're going to trim the scope to fit the amount of
money and the amount of time that we have left to finish the next phase or are we going to go all the
way to the end of the project so things were successful here we got over a big risk a big hurdle we
have a big deliverable.
Now we're going to continue and go to all the way to the end of the project or just the opposite a Kill
Point.
We're going to in the project.
Are you going to remain the face.
Are you not able to move forward because you didn't hit your goals that the scope was not met that these
things are not of quality and there are some issues.
So we have to complete the scope before you can move forward.
So the scope for that phase or do you have to repeat the phase that maybe did some testing and things
of quality.
So youve got to repeat the phase or certain parts of it have to be updated.
So the different elements of the fates so business documents will see throughout the course were talking
about things like feasibility the business case project documents estimates things like that things
that support the project and that should tell us where we should be at the end of these different phases.
All right good job.